<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bookshelf>
  <book>
    <title>The New Basics: A-to-Z Baby &amp; Child Care for the Modern Parent</title>
    <author>Michel Cohen</author>
    <comments>
      Some very odd advice, like in the section titled Washing he says
      to bathe your baby "every once in a while". Toothbrushing? He
      says don't bother until 12 to 15 months while any dentist will
      tell you to brush teeth as soon as there are teeth to brush.
      <p>
      The attempt at clever writing gets old, such as labeling the
      evening the Witching Hour and saying that "Lucy's trick ain't no
      treat". The repeated suggestion to "allow her to cry out her
      frustrations" is sad.
      <p>
      While many topics are covered lots of them don't really say
      anything like the one paragraph on twins that says, (Really!)
      "The particular thing about twins is that well, obviously, there
      are two of them". Another odd one, toilet training is
      "unnecessary" because children will learn this on their own. In
      regards to fears, he says to treat them "in a controlled,
      dismissive manner" since "he'll eventually realize by himself
      that what he is scared of is not that scary."
      <p>
      The author's solution for colic is to "leave Lucy to cry in dim
      light and warmth in the bassinet".
      <p>
      The book is disrespectful to any health professional who does
      not carry an MD after their name. Midwives and lacation
      consultants are poked fun at and he recommends using them for
      emotional support only and asking a family member for the real
      advice on breastfeeding.
      <p>
      The fact that the advice for many subjects is that "they will
      pass in a few months" is not helpful during the process. To
      answer the question "Is it true that you can't spoil a baby?" He
      answers: "You can't exactly spoil your baby, but you can spoil
      your life"
      <p>
      I'd pass on this one.
    </comments>
  </book>
</bookshelf> 
